Let him go.
让我走
Now then - turn off that machine.
既然如此, 关掉机器
I have to report that we have lost the trace.
It was operating only a few moments.
我不得不说我们跟丢了, 它仅仅只开启了一小会儿
We are not interested in excuses.
Find them! Find them! Find them!
我们对接口不感兴趣！找到他们, 找到他们, 找到他们！
No last words of repentance, Sir Reginald?
死到临头了你忏悔不, Reginald 爵士？
No, only that you're making one fundamental mistake...
不, 你犯了一个很基础的错误...
That is?
是什么?
A question of mistaken identity.
I am not Sir Reginald Styles.
你认错人了, 我不是 Reginald Styles 爵士
Is that the best you can do?
你最多也就只能这样？
But it's true! Sir Reginald...
但这是事实！Reginald 爵士他...
Sir Reginald is at this moment
many thousands of miles away -
Reginald 爵士这会儿正在千里之外
in Peking, to be precise.
确切地说, 在北京
You are lying.
你在撒谎
No, I'm not. He flew there yesterday.
不, 我没有。他昨天就飞过去了
I do not believe you.
我不相信你
It's all there in the paper in front of you.
Why don't you take a look?
这全都在你面前的报纸上, 你为什么不看一眼？
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
很抱歉让你失望了
It's a trick - kill him now!
这是个伎俩 - 现在就杀了他！
If you are not Sir Reginald Styles
如果你不是 Reginald Styles
who are you and what are you doing in his house?
那你是谁, 你在他的房子里做什么？
Well, believe it or believe it not,
I came here to see you.
嗯, 不知道你们信不信, 我是来见你们的
We're wasting time, Anat. Here, I'll do it.
我们这是在浪费时间, Anat。来, 我来下手
Who is in command of this mission?!
这次任务谁是指挥官？！
We are soldiers, not murderers.
Keep guard outside, I'll deal with these two.
我们是战士, 不是杀人犯。出去警戒, 我来对付这两个
I said out!
我说了出去
Now then, answer my question -
who are you and what are you doing here?
接下里, 回答我的问题 - 你是谁, 在这里做什么？
- I wanted to talk to you.  - Why?
- 我想来跟你们谈谈  - 为什么？
To find out where you came from.
And more to the point - when.
为了搞明白你们从哪里来, 更重要的是, 从何时来
- Two soldiers approach.  - Hide!
- 有两个士兵过来了  - 躲起来！
Down there!
下去!
Hurry!
快！
Captain Yates, sir, on four.
是 Yates 队长, 头儿, 四号线
I can't speak to him now.
我现在没法跟他通话
He says something very odd
is happening at Auderly House./56.4
他说 Auderly House 那边出了非常奇怪的事情
If you could have a quick word with him, sir?
你能更他简单说几句吗, 头儿？
All right.
好吧
Yes, what is it, Yates?
是我, 什么事, Yates？
A couple of my men missing, sir,
and the Doctor and Miss Grant -
有几个我的人不见了, 头儿, 还有博士和Grant小姐
- not a sign of them
- Look really, Yates,
- 他们一点踪迹没有  - 听着, 真的, Yate
I've got a major international crisis on.
I really haven't got time for any...
我这里有一个严重的国际危机, 我真的没时间来...
- Oh, Lethbridge-Stewart?
- Erm, yes, yes, that's right
- 哦, Lethbridge-Stewart?  - 呃, 是的是的，我就是
- Yes, it's the Minister here.
- One moment, sir.
- 是的, 部长在这里  - 稍等, 先生
Listen, Yates, search the grounds again
or report back to me - out!
听着 Yates, 再次搜一下地面, 回报结果给我 - 挂了！
Yes, Minister?
好了, 部长
Right, they're clear of the house. Have you finished?
好了, 他们撤离这栋房子了。你完成了吗？
- Yes.  - We must go.
- 是的  - 我们得走了
Quietly!
安静！
Oh, that's better.
噢, 好多了
You know, I've got a good mind
to let you stay like that!
你知道吧, 我最好让你保持那样！
So much more peaceful.
安静多了
In any case, even if I released you,
you'll probably ask me a lot of fool questions!
不管怎样, 如果我放开你, 你就很可能问我很多傻问题！
I've only got one question - who are they?
我就只有一个问题  - 他们是谁？
On the face of it, three rather desperate people.
一方面看, 是三个挺绝望的人
Well, they're criminals - they must be!
当然, 他们是罪犯 - 他们肯定是
Ah, you're prejudiced.
啊, 你这是偏见
Well, aren't you? They tried to kill you and me.
那你不是？他们试图杀了你和我
That's not in their favour, I'll admit.
那对他们也没什么好处, 我得承认
You know, we shouldn't really judge 'em
until we find out why they're here.
在我们搞明白他们为什么到这里来之前, 我们不能乱下断言
We are maintaining constant watch,
我们在持续监视
but there is no sign of any
time transference module in operation.
但没有发现时间传送模块运转的迹象
All criminal elements must be
tracked down and destroyed.
所有的犯罪行为必须要追踪到, 要消灭
Well, I am doing everything possible, but...
是的, 我正在尽一切可能, 但是...
They will have returned to the time zone
where the first criminal was eliminated.
他们将会返回原时区, 也就是第一个罪犯被消灭的地方
You will dispatch security forces to search for them.
你得派遣安全部队去搜寻
Of course... at once.
当然... 马上执行
And the new equipment?
那新设备呢？
The Time Vortex Magnetron is set to the frequency
of the module that was traced.
时间涡流磁控管的频率, 已经调到与被追踪的模块一致了
Anyone using that module will be diverted
in the space-time vortex and attracted here.
任何人使用那个模块, 都会被时空涡流转移到这里来
But only if that particular module is used?
但只有使用那个特定的模块才会这样吧？
It is necessary to know the frequency.
知道频率是很有必要的
But surely no one will use the module?
They must realise that we can trace them...
但肯定没人将会使用这个模块？他们肯定意识到我们可以...
Do not dispute with the Daleks!
The function of the human is to obey!
不要跟 Dalek 争辩！人类的功能就是服从！
Activate the Magnetron!
激活磁控管！
...to base. Intercept to base. Do you coordinate?/?
..呼叫基地, 拦截小组呼叫基地, 你们能定位吗？
Do you coordinate? Intercept...
你们能定位吗？拦截小组...
No good. There is a massive disturbance in the vortex.
没效果。涡流里面干扰太强了
We cannot fail again. This is our last chance.
我们不能再失败了, 这是我们最后的机会
We must get fresh orders.
The time coordinates are crucial.
我们必须获得最新的命令, 时间坐标非常关键
We cannot wait for new orders!
我们等不起新命令了！
Look, why don't I return to the tunnel?
There's better chance of contact there.
听着, 我为什么不回到隧道去？在那里联系的话机会大些
Right, Shura. Ask them...
对, Shura, 问问他们...
Why ask them anything?
Isn't it obvious what we must do?
为什么所有事情都要问他们？我们必须做什么不是很明显吗？
We wait here and kill Styles.
我们在这里等着 Styles 出现, 杀了他
And if we are detected?
如果我们被发现了了？
We hold those two as hostages.
We kill them if necessary.
我们拿这两个人做人质, 必要的话杀了他们
Get alternative orders.
去看看有没有新指令吧
Right.
好
What do you mean, missing?
你是什么意思, “失踪”？
Well, there's not a sign of them.
就是, 没有他们的任何踪迹
We searched the house and the grounds, sir.
我们搜索了房子, 还有地面, 头儿
The Doctor, Jo and a couple of my men - vanished.
博士, Jo, 还有我的几个人 - 都消失了
Now listen, Yates, I've been talking to the Minister.
给我听着, Yates, 我已经跟部长通过电话了
Styles seems to have pulled it off. The Chinese
have agreed to attend and the conference is on again.
Styles 似乎成功了, 中国同意出席, 会议又要召开了
Oh, when's it fixed for?
哦, 那定在什么时候？
Tomorrow night, so you see the spot this puts me in!
明天晚上, 所以你明白我现在的处境了吧？
Get me Auderly House!
给我接 Auderly House!
Where is he?
他在哪儿？
I told you, Anat.
我告诉过你, Anat
I just don't understand. I mean,
why don't they go back to September 12th
我就是搞不明白。我是说, 为什么他们不回到9月12号去
if that's where they want to be -
you know, have another go.
如果那是他们想去的日子的话 - 就是说, 再来一次
Well, that's the Blinovitch limitation effect.
哦, 那就是 Blinovitch 限制效应
The what?
什么效应？
On your feet, both of you!
站起来, 你们两个都是！
Honestly, sir. You're wasting your time -
he's not there.
说实话, 先生, 你是在浪费自己的时间 - 他并不在那儿
Hello? Hello?
哈啰？ 哈啰？
Doctor?
博士吗？
Yes?
哪位？
Lethbridge-Stewart.
是 Lethbridge-Stewart.
Ah.
啊
Is everything all right there?
那边一切都好吗？
Yes fine, Brigadier.
Yes, things couldn't be better.
是的都好, 准将, 是的, 不能更好了
Yates and Benton came to look for you.
Said the place was deserted.
Yates 和 Benton 过去找你, 说那个地方都没人了
Did they? Oh yes, we were probably
down the cellar at the time.
是吗？哦是了, 我们那会儿很可能正在酒窖里面
Old Styles keeps a remarkably
good selection of wines, you know.
老 Styles 收藏了很多不错的葡萄酒, 你知道吗？
Now listen, Doctor, you're sure that
everything is normal down at that house?
听着, 博士, 你确定那个房子里一切都正常？
Because Styles is coming back there tomorrow night.
因为 Styles 明天晚上就会回到那里去
Look, I... I don't think that's very wise, Brigadier...
哦, 我...我觉得那样不是太明智, 准将...
Well, why not if everything's all right?
啊, 为什么不明智, 既然一切都好？
It is all right, isn't it, Doctor?
Captain Yates was very concerned about you.
的确没事, 是吧, 博士？Yates 队长很担心你
Well, you tell Captain Yates not to worry,
everything's fine.
好, 你告诉 Yates 队长不用担心, 一切都好
And tell old Styles too, and the Prime Minister.
也告诉老 Styles, 还有首相
Right.
好的
Oh, and Brigadier?
哦, 对了准将？
Yes?
怎么？
Don't forget to tell it to the marines. Goodbye.
别忘了告诉 Marines, 再见
(Marines 即海军陆战队，博士这里是把它说得好像是某个人名似的)
There you are, sir. I said there was something wrong.
看吧, 头儿, 我就说这里有事
I'm going down to that house myself.
我要亲自到那栋房子去
Lay on a jeep for me, will you?
I'll meet you there later.
给我安排辆吉普, 好吗？我一会儿再哪里跟你汇合
He's coming! Sir Reginald Styles is coming here.
他要来了, Reginald 爵士要过来了
Well that surprises you? Well, I should have thought
with your insight into the future...
让你感到意外了吧？fixme
oh no, in your case, it'd be the past, wouldn't it?
哦不对, 在你看来, 应该是过去, 是吧？
The conference tomorrow night -
our dates were right after all.
会议是在明天晚上 - 我们的日期终究还是对了
All we have to do is to wait here
until he returns and then...
我们唯一要做的, 就是在这里等着他回来, 然后...
Right! Drop your guns! If you don't,
I'll smash this to pieces.
听着！放下你们的枪？如果不放, 我就把你们轰成渣
Jo, put that thing down.
I've only just got it in working order.
Jo, 把那个东西放下, 我只是让它勉强可以工作
I mean it.
我说真的
Stupid child! You do not know what you are doing!
蠢孩子！你知不知道自己在做什么！
Oh yes I do - you're going to let us both out
- or you'll be stranded here for ever.
噢我知道  - 要么你放我们俩出去, 要么你们就永远被困在这里
We don't need that machine. We have another one.
我们不需要那个机器, 我们另外有一个
The man who owned that machine is dead.
His body is back in our time zone.
那个机器的主人已经死了, 它的尸体就在我们时区
You're... bluffing.
你在...唬我呢？
Put it down and don't be silly!
把它放下, 别犯傻
Jo, do as she says.
Jo, 按她说的做
Drop it... drop it!
放下...放下!
Jo! Jo!
Look, can't you do anything?
嘿, 你就不能做点什么吗？
No, it's too late.
不能, 太迟了
Well, what... what's happened to her?
那, 什么...她这到底发生了什么？
Disintegrated, dispersed around the time vortex.
被分解了, 散到时间涡流里面去了
If she was lucky.
——这还算幸运的
And if she wasn't?
那如果她不幸运呢？
Re-embodied in the twenty-second century.
会在22世纪重组
Believe me, she would be better off dead.
相信我, 她最好是死了
You may go.
你可以走了
You see, they're really not as terrifying as they look.
你看, 他们真的并不像看起来那么可怕
What are they?
他们是什么？
Ogrons. They're a form of higher anthropoid.
Ogron, 他们是一种高级的类人猿
They used to live in scattered communities
on one of the outer planets.
他们以前分散居住在一颗系外行星上
They make very useful servants.
是很有用的奴仆
Servants? Well, what do they do?
奴仆？那, 他们做些什么？
Oh, we use them as... policemen.
哦, 我们用他们做...警察
They're very simple, very honest, very loyal.
他们都非常简单、诚实, 还很忠诚
Do please sit down.
请坐
Thank you.
谢谢你
Is this really the... twenty-second century?
这里真的是...22世纪？
Oh, don't worry. We can return you to your own time, /?
哦, 别担心, 我们可以把你送回你的时间
but, er, tell me Miss, erm?
但是, 告诉我, 你是...？
Grant, Jo Grant.
Grant, 我叫 Jo Grant
Miss Grant... these three people
who attacked you - what did you make of them?
Grant 小姐... 袭击你的这三个人 - 你怎么看他们？
Well, they were sort of... guerillas, I suppose.
唔, 他们像是...游击队员, 我觉得
They are cruel and ruthless fanatics.
他们是些残忍无情的狂热分子
You know who they are?
你知道他们是谁？
Unfortunately, yes. But what you don't know,
is how lucky you are
很不幸，知道。但你不知道的是，你有多幸运
that they didn't get rid of you straight away.
他们居然没有直接干掉你
They tried to kill the Doctor.
他们试图杀死博士
He's still with them, is he - this friend of yours?
他还跟他们在一起，是吧 - 你的这个朋友
Yes, they're holding him prisoner.
是的，他们把他扣押了
Then I am afraid he is in very grave danger.
那我觉得他的处境恐怕非常危险
But they've no reason to harm him!
They know he's the wrong man!
但他们没有理由伤害他! 他们知道要找的不是他!
You don't know these people!
We have spent years trying to track them down.
你不了解这些人! 我们花了多年时间试图追踪到他们
If you knew some of the terrifying crimes
they have been capable of!
要知道他们能犯下一些可怕的罪行!
If anyone stands in their way, they are without mercy.
如果有人挡了他们的道, 他们就毫不留情
I can believe it.
这我相信
However, there is a chance that
I may be able to save your friend.
不过，还是有一线可能我可以救下你的朋友
Could you?!
能吗？
I can try. There are means but I shall need your help.
我可以试试。是有一些方法，但我需要你的帮助
Well, how can I help?
好，我能帮上什么？
Well, first of all, I shall want to know exactly
where you came from... and when.
哦，首先，我得知道你确切地从哪里来...以及时间
Well, we were at Sir Reginald Styles' house,
about... fifty miles from London.
哦，我们当时在 Reginald Styles 爵士的房子...离伦敦大约50英里
Now, you've told me the year,
can you tell me the exact date?
现在，你告诉我年份，你能说出具体的日期吗？
That's easy - it was September the 13th.
那很容易 - 是9月13日
Excellent.
非常好
Now, you must be tired, you must be hungry.
We do have special guest rooms.
现在，你肯定累了也饿了。我们这里有特别的客人房间
Leave everything to me.
Oh, there is one last question...
一切都留给我吧。哦，还有最后一个问题...
these criminals - can you tell me exactly
where they entered your time?
这些罪犯 - 你能否告诉我，他们具体从何处进入你们的时间线？
I mean, did they manifest themselves in the house itself?
我是说，他们是在房子里面突然现身的吗？
I don't think so.
我觉得不是
Somewhere outside the house - some hiding place?
那是在房子外面某个地方 - 某个可以躲藏的地方？
I don't know for sure, but there's a tunnel
by a canal, not far from the house.
我不是太确定，但运河边有个隧道，离房子不太远
We found that... time machine there.
我们是在那里找到那个...时间机器的
A tunnel? Thank you.
I'll call you as soon as we have any news.
一个隧道？谢谢你。我们一有消息就会来叫你
You see? She trusts me implicitly.
看到了吗？她一来就信任我了
The criminals are using the tunnel as a transfer point.
那些罪犯在使用隧道作为传送点
We will prepare an ambush
in the twentieth-century time zone.
我们将在20世纪的时区准备一次伏击
We have security forces in the area.
我们在该地区有安全部队
With any luck, they will drive the guerillas
straight into our hands.
如果运气好的话, 他们会把游击队直接驱赶到我们手里
Anat! Look!
Anat! 快看！
Shoot!
开火！
Pull back!
撤回来
We can get through the library. Come!
我们可以穿过图书馆，快
Stay where you are! Boaz, get out!
呆着别的。Boaz, 出来
Boaz, come on!
Boaz, 快点！
Come on, Boaz, out! Out, out!
快，Boaz，出去！出去出去！
How do you do?
你好吗？
Doctor, what on earth's going on?
博士，这里到底怎么回事？
Thank you, Brigadier, for that timely intervention.
谢谢你, 准将, 感谢你的及时干预
Who is that creature.
那个怪物是什么东西
Yes, well, I'll explain about him later.
Excuse me, old chap, I'm in a hurry.
是的, 好吧, 我以后再解释他的事。对不起, 老伙计, 我赶时间